A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release
And his tail drew the third part of the stars of heaven,
and did cast them to the earth:
and the dragon stood before the woman
which was ready to be delivered,
for to devour her child as soon as it was born.
- (Revelations 12:4)
（男１）うあ  ああっ
う… うあーっ！
（男２）はっ！
ケエッ！
ハァ ハァ
予測データどおりの動きだったな
Her movements fit perfectly with the data's prediction.
Target acquired. Target acquired.
Regroup. Patrol surrounding area for enemy fire.
Emergency com use only.
（ヒトミ）ちょっと どいてよ！
Step aside, would you?!
Target acquired. Target acquired.
The problem with these tranquilizer rounds
is that they burst the body.
この麻酔弾は外傷が残るのが問題ね
（ブリアレオス･ヘカトンケイレス）
そうだ  デュナン･ナッツの確保だ
That's her. Deunan Knute has been secured!
きれいな人…
She's beautiful...
（ヒトミ）８時間12分
よく眠ってるわ
8 hours, 12 minutes.
She sure knows how to sleep.
伝説の戦士も
寝顔はかわいいわね
For a legendary she's awfully cute when she sleeps.
その体のことって…
Do you think she knows about your body?
目覚めたら驚くわね
She's bound to be amazed!
At seeing our Utopia.
私たちのユートピアに
（ブリアレオス）ユートピアね
Utopia, huh...?
（ES.W.A.T.通信員）
オリュンポスAF-５
着陸許可はまだか
Olympus AF5, we are requesting permission to land.
（ヒトミ）ＩＤ確認前に
あまり接近しないでね
Keep a wide berth until they confirm our ID.
多脚砲台に蜂の巣にされちゃうわよ
Otherwise the Mobile Fortress
will fill us full of holes.
（ES.W.A.T.通信員）
オリュンポスAF-５ こちら…
Olympus Af5, this is...
Identification's verified.
Proceed to platforms.
着陸許可を確認
Landing clearance confirmed.
（ブリアレオス）
ES.W.A.T.　Ｇ-２ Ａ-９
これより着陸態勢に入る
This is ES.W.A.T. G2E9.
Commencing landing procedure.
（デュナン）ブリアレオス
Briareos!
I'm going up ahead to scout around.
（ブリアレオス）
その先まで偵察に行ってくる
私も行く
I'll come with you.
おまえはここにいろ
No, Deunan. Stay here.
大丈夫  すぐ戻る
Relax. I'll be back before you know it.
ブリアレオス…
Briareos...
So, I see you gave her a full work-up.
（ヒトミ）今回は ずいぶん
念入りのチェックだったのね
立法院からの指示どおりに
Just following orders from the Legislature.
Can't believe she's still asleep...
まだ 眠ってる
麻酔の配合 間違えたかしら
Maybe we gave her the wrong dose of anesthesia?
動くと首の骨をへし折るぞ
Move and I'll snap your neck!
（ブリアレオス）
デュナン･ナッツ 第２小隊長！
2nd Platoon Leader Deunan Knute,
stand down at once!
戦闘態勢をとけ！
ブリアレオス？
Briareos...
信じられない
I don't believe it.
無理もないわ
でも これが現実なの
I know this is hard, but the facts are there, Deunan.
Are you saying that after all those years of fighting
結局 あれだけの規模の世界大戦で
どの国も勝利しなかったと言うの？
there was no clear winner to the Global War?
そう
そして かつての総合管理局―
Right. And now Olympus governs the world.
The ruling body is comprised of the former
General Administration Agency.
つまり 現在の このオリュンポスが
世界を治めたのよ
（デュナン）じゃあ 私は
何も知らされないまま―
So, for months
I've been fighting one meaningless battle
after another without knowing anything.
何ヵ月も意味のない戦いを
繰り返していたってわけ？
戦争なんてそんなもんでしょう？
Well, that's war for you.
（ヒトミ）だけど ここは違うわ
But in Olympus mankind has finally
achieved its state of Utopia
オリュンポスこそ 人類がようやく
辿り着いたユートピアなの
in a fair and balanced society.
（デュナン）
なぜ 私をここへ？
So, what do you need me for?
それは あなたが
優秀な戦士だからよ
Even an ideal society still requires great warriors.
あなたの名前は ES.W.A.T.(エスワット)の ヒト
強化リストのトップに挙がってるの
ES.W.A.T. has had you on the top of the
reinforcement list for some time now.
で… 私の仕事は
あなたのような選ばれたヒトを
You see, it's my job to find elite soldiers
from the outside world, such as yourself,
外部世界からオリュンポスに
迎え入れることなのよ
and bring them here to Olympus.
ES.W.A.T.?
“ES.W.A.T.”？
聞きたいことは
山ほどあると思うけど―
I'm sure you must have a lot of questions,
but let's leave them till tomorrow, all right?
とにかく今晩はゆっくり休んで
For now, just get some rest.
続きは明日(あした)
街を案内しながらってことで
I'll swing by in the morning and give you a tour.
I just know you're going to like it here,
our little Utopia.
きっと デュナンも気に入るわよ
私たちのユートピア
Your bedroom is right in here.
ベッドルームはこっちね
It must be ages since you slept in a warm bed.
（ヒトミ）やわらかいベッドは
久しぶりでしょう？
I'll pick you up at 10 am sharp.
明日(あした)は10時に迎えにくるから
Hitomi... That's your name, right?
ヒトミ… だったわよね？
Correct.
そうよ
Do we know each other?
前にどこかで？
フフ  いいえ
それじゃあ  おやすみなさい
I don't think so. Good night.
I'll see you in the morning.
（デュナン）いつ…？
When did you...
（ブリアレオス）北アフリカ戦線で
体を失った  もう１年になる
On the North African front.
My body was badly damaged.
That was a year ago.
（ブリアレオス）カールの…
It was Carl's...
A keepsake of your father.
親父さんの形見だろ？
没収されると 厄介だからな
Don't let it get confiscated.
Call me if you need anything.
（ブリアレオス）
何かあったら呼んでくれ
Briareos...
ブリアレオス…
Do you have any idea who attacked me up there?
あの襲ってきた連中に
心当たりは？
No.
ない
（七賢老）悲しいよ―
Oh, very sad.
It was you who woke a straight
adept attack, wasn't it, Athena?
あの襲撃は アテナの仕業だね
A few greedy mercenaries are
no threat to ES.W.A.T., are they?
（七賢老）カネ目当ての傭兵など
ES.W.A.T.の敵ではないだろう？
（七賢老）バイオロイドの使命を
忘れてしまったのかい
Have you forgotten the Bioroid's primary mission?
（七賢老）軍部にしれたら
ウラノス将軍の思う壺だよ
If the military finds out,
support for the General will grow.
（七賢老）
もう我々の力では抑えきれない
General Uranus is beyond our control now.
And the limit of Gaia's tolerance
may have been reached.
（七賢老）ガイアも
もはや限界かもしれない
Athena,
（七賢老）アテナ
もう あまり時間がないのだよ
the little time we have left is running out.
Nike!
（アテナ･アレイアス）
ニケ！
We have a leak.
筒抜けだ
I'm sorry, Prime Minister.
（ニケ）申し訳ありません
Nike,
ニケ  ES.W.A.T.に内偵が必要だ
I wanna covered investigation of ES.W.A.T.
I'll arrange it immediately.
（ニケ）すぐに手配します
We barely averted a total disaster.
（アテナ）
だが 最悪の事態は免れた
探しものは見つからなかった
It's lucky for us they didn't find it.
Then you mean...
それでは？
Looks like they didn't do anything rash
like a full cerebral scan.
外科的手段という愚行には
及ばなかったようだ
しかし 火の粉は
払いのけなければなるまい
But still we'd be fools to believe this was over.
なんとしても デュナン･ナッツを
確保せよ
I want you to make sure I have Deunan Knute!
（ニケ）はい
Yes, Ma'am!
ヒトとは 自分から進んで檻に入る
珍しい動物だな
What a strange creature is Man that
he would choose to cage himself so willingly.
ハデス大佐が
直接 お見えになるとは
It is indeed an honor to have you
here in person, Colonel Hades.
（ハデス大佐）
ES.W.A.T.は―
As we speak the members of ES.W.A.T.
are desperately chasing a decoy.
今ごろ血まなこになって
ダミーを追っているよ
現時点で 98パーセントの
準備が整っております
Your body is nearly complete, Sir,
for assembly stands at 98 percent.
（ハデス）素晴らしい
Magnificent...
特注パーツから足がつく危険も
すべて消去いたしました
The special parts requests weren't easy to come by.
but rest's assured. They can never be traced.
ウラノス将軍もお喜びだろう
General Uranus will be pleased.
これ以上 バイオロイドたちの
思うようにはさせない！
It begins.
The Bioroids will no longer have their way.
Yes, I agree, but that does not
change business circumstances.
（七賢老）
我々が守るべきなのは―
狼ではなく羊を旨とする人々
ではなかったかな
Our goal is to protect the sheep not the wolves.
First generation Bioroids like Athena
lack sufficient restraints.
（七賢老）確かに
第１期バイオロイドは抑制が希薄だ
（七賢老）より タチの悪い狼は
羊の皮を被っているがね
It would seem the proverbial wolf has
donned itself in sheep's clothing.
（七賢老）しかし―
True.
狼であれ羊であれ １人の犠牲者も
出すわけにはいかない
But whether wolf or sheep, we cannot
allow a single person to be hurt.
（七賢老）哀れだな
It is useless.
結論は すでに出ているというのに
The outcome's known.
It's always been acknowledged.
（七賢老）それでも 我々は議論を
続けなければならない
Not even so, that is all the more reason to continue our debate.
（七賢老）さあ 再びガイアとの
対話を 始めましょう
Agreed.
Let us resume our consultation with Gaia.
（ブリアレオス）デュナン！
Deunan!
ブリアレオス！
Briareos!
（ヒトミ）おはよう  デュナン
Good morning, Deunan.
ウフ
よく似合ってるわ
さあ 乗って！
You look terrific.
Hop in.
（ヒトミ）今朝 正式に
入職が許可されたわ
Your immigration papers were finalized this morning.
これで デュナンも
オリュンポスの一員ってことね
You are now an official citizen of Olympus.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
（ヒトミ）美しい街でしょう？
昨日までの光景を考えると
まぼろしを見ているようね
Considering where I was until yesterday,
this all seems like a mirage.
（ヒトミ）今日からはこれが現実よ
Well, as of today it's reality.
（デュナン）みんな幸せそう
Everyone seems so happy.
That's because half of the city's
population is pure Bioroid.
この街の住人の50パーセントが
バイオロイドだからよ
Bioroid?
バイオロイド？
（ヒトミ）創造されたヒト
Manufactured humans.
You mean clones?
（デュナン）クローンのこと？
Not just ordinary clones,
単一クローンでなく―
優良種混合のハイブリッドに
加工を施した優れものよ
but an advanced hybrid species made
from the highest quality components.
この街は クローンなんかに
支配されてるってこと？
Let me get this straight.
The whole city is run by just clones?
クローンなんかって失礼ね
私もそのバイオロイドなんだけど
Pardon me, but "just clones"...?
You didn't know I was the Bioroid too, did you?
What!?
Meanwhile our composition maybe superior to yours,
それに優良種だからといって―
バイオロイドがヒトを支配している
わけではないの
Bioroids in no way attempt to control human beings.
（ヒトミ）バイオロイドは
ヒト社会の安定を目指して―
Our role is to stabilize an otherwise
turbulent human society.
ヒトとヒトの緩衝材としての
役割を担っているの
We're facilitators of balance and peace.
半分が バイオロイド
Half the city is Bioroid...
This car seems sort of strange.
（デュナン）この車 何か変
It has one of the new prototype
Damysos systems installed.
まだ開発中のダミュソスシステムを
搭載しているの
Meaning what?
ダミュソス？
It's a floating car.
（ヒトミ）
つまり 浮いてるってこと
長生きはするものよね
Live long enough and you'll see everything I guess.
（デュナン）超振動による
重力制御が完成しているの？
They've achieved gravity control
through high frequency oscillation?
And you control it by the steering wheel, right?
（デュナン）でも 運転は
そのハンドルだけ？
この街じゃ こんなものまで
サイボーグ感覚ってわけ
Everything has cyborg sensors
now just like this car.
The basis of our modern design is
"human-centered and user-friendly".
それもこれも 人間中心の
考え方が基本にあるから
（ヒトミ）“原理は単純を
構造は複雑を極め―”
"Conceptual simplicity, structural complexity
achieves the greater state of humanity."
“ヒトは もっともヒトらしく”
ってね
Right?
What is that?
何それ？
It's the Central Planning Bureau's
model for Olympus design
都市企画班が維持機関に送った言葉
その象徴的存在があれ
the City Maintenance Department swears by.
And there's the shining symbol:
Tartarus and Daedalus.
“タルタロス”と“ダイダロス”
あそこにはオリュンポスを管理する
Inside those two amazing structures
is the enormous I.N. brain
巨大な“ＩＮ(アイエヌ)”の
ブレインが収められているの
which runs all of Olympus.
（デュナン）“ＩＮ”？
I.N.?
"Intelligence Network".
（ヒトミ）インテリジェンスド･
ネットワークのこと
We nicknamed it Gaia.
通称“ガイア”
Gaia is the self-expanding network that
monitors all aspects of daily life here in the city.
（ヒトミ）
ガイアは自己増殖しながら―
オリュンポスの全体を
監視しているの
特に 私たち バイオロイドをね
Mainly our Bioroid interaction...
With human beings?
何のために？
Correct. Humans are ruled by unstable emotions.
ほら…
ヒトの感情って不安定でしょう？
Their inherent anger often leads to war.
すぐケンカしたり 戦争を始めたり
その点  バイオロイドは
感情を抑制されているから
But in Bioroids emotional reactions are suppressed.
We harbor no anger or jealousy
towards other people.
嫉妬心もないし
他人を恨んだりもしないの
And that's how we've been able to the peace.
だから 争いごとも
起きないってわけ
However at the top of Tartarus
is a virus tank called "D-Tank"
（ヒトミ）でもタルタロスの
頂上には―
完全な防御システムに守られた―
which is guarded by the ultimate
system in high-tech security.
“Ｄタンク”と呼ばれる
ウイルスタンクがあってー
If the virus was ever released,
it would wipe out all Bioroid existence.
それを発動すると
いつでもバイオロイドを
絶滅できると言われているの
I know it's man's need for self-preservation,
ヒトの防衛本能の産物らしいけど
全く失礼しちゃうわ
but that doesn't make it any less insulting.
Meaning humans pose the bigger threat?
ヒトのほうが
よっぽど危険ってこと？
I mean it's vital to maintain a balance between us.
（ヒトミ）だから その両者の
バランスが大切なの  ガイアは―
That's why Gaia also monitors
the emotional effect of Bioroids on humans.
バイオロイドがヒトに与える
精神的な影響を監視しているの
In other words it makes sure we
humans don't get out of line.
（デュナン）じゃあ
監視されてるのはヒトのほうね
（ヒトミ）
ウラノス将軍みたいな言い方ね
You're starting to sound like General Uranus.
Who's that?
（デュナン）誰？
Commander of the Olympus Regular Army
オリュンポス正規軍の総司令
And an extremist to the highest order.
バイオロイドを目の敵にしてる
極端な懐古主義者なの
He opposes all Bioroids.
Sounds like Utopia isn't the General's cup of tea.
ユートピアには
似つかわしくない存在ね
The Olympus governing body
is comprised entirely of Bioroids.
オリュンポスの行政は すべて
バイオロイドが担当してるの
Prime Minister Athena is one as well.
アテナ総監もバイオロイドだし
Athena?
アテナ？
ア… アテナ
Athena...
Oh, have the two of you met before?
アテナ総監を知っているの？
I don't see how we could have.
多分 知らない
I guess you could say she is
our Commander-in-Chief.
（ヒトミ）
総監って大統領みたいなものね
Although humans are still in charge of the military.
でも 軍部はヒトが指揮しているの
怖いでしょう
Kinda scary, huh?
Anyway ES.W.A.T. is led by Prime Minister Athena
under the authority of the Administration.
（ヒトミ）最近 アテナ総監率いる
行政院管轄の―
ES.W.A.T.の勢力が増大して
アーミー化しているわ
It's almost grown into an army onto itself.
で… 正規軍と折り合いが
悪くなってきたの
And that's not winning her
any friends with the regular army.
Of course neither one of them has
final authority over Olympus.
でも オリュンポスのすべての
最終意思決定は―
That's entrusted to Gaia.
ガイアに委ねられている
Hm, what's wrong?
あ… どうしたの？
We're being followed.
（デュナン）つけられてる
ええいっ
（デュナン）
ヒトミ… 大丈夫？
Hitomi, are you hurt?
I'm all right.
なんとかね  でも あれ…
But it's not over...
Not too friendly looking, are they?
いかにもって連中ね
それで？  狙いは私？
If I had to I'd guess they are after me.
Good guess.
間違いなく
Yup, this is reality, all right.
やっぱり  これが現実ね
Briareos!
ブリアレオス！
The Appleseed seal must never be unlocked.
（サイボーグ）アップル…シードノ
封印ヲ…解いてハイケ…
Hello, Elders, how are you feeling?
ご機嫌いかが？
おじいちゃんたち
Hitomi, thank goodness you're safe.
（七賢老）ヒトミ
無事だったんだね
You weren't hurt, were you?
怪我はないかい？
I'm fine. No need to worry.
私は大丈夫よ
They're so protective.
それより お待ちかねの
デュナン･ナッツを連れて来たわよ
Anyway, here she is, Ms. Deunan Knute.
おお  噂に違わぬ美人だ
The rumors of your beauty do not do your justice.
The Goddess of War.
闘いの女神
How lovely, you have your father's eyes.
目元などはカールによく似てる
Excuse me, but did you know my father?
父をご存知なのですか？
Well, of course, my dear.
知っているも何も―
オリュンポスの
バイオロイドの大半が―
Everyone knows about the great Colonel Knute.
カール･ナッツ大佐の遺伝子の
一部を受け継いでいるんだよ
Most Bioroids in Olympus carry a trace
of Carl's DNA within their systems.
（七賢老）だから ヒトミだって
デュナンとは姉妹のようなもの
Which makes you and Hitomi
almost like sisters, genetically speaking.
しかし 着いてそうそう
嫌な思いをさせたね
We regret what happened to you earlier...
and so soon after your arrival.
最近は 外部の人間を
歓迎しない輩が多くてね
A sign of the times.
Violence against those from
the outside world has risen lately.
（七賢老）
バランスが崩れるのを恐れている
Some fear our society is losing its delicate balance.
さあ まずはガイアに紹介しよう
Later. Let us first introduce you to Gaia.
（エドワード･ウラノス３世）
騒がしくなってきたな
I heard there had been some excitement.
（ハデス）
立法と行政に対立が見られます
The Legislature and the Administration are at odds.
バイオロイドの増長が
顕著になってきている証拠かと
This dispute only proves how arrogant
the Bioroids have become.
（ウラノス）アテナが追っている
のは 本当にカールの娘なのか？
Are you certain Prime Minister Athena
is searching for Carl's daughter?
（ハデス）間違いありません
Absolutely, Sir.
すべての準備は整っています
Everything stands at the ready.
情報源の確度は？
How reliable is our intelligence?
レベル５に値します
Extremely. Level 5.
将軍 ご決断を
General, we need a decision!
ヒトを魂の道具にさせてはいけない
I will never allow humans to become living tools.
これが ガイア？
So, this is Gaia...
Gaia was designed to be a self-propagating network
（七賢老）ガイアはネットワークを
自ら成長させ―
which oversees and administers all of Olympus.
オリュンポスを管理しているんだよ
そして ガイアと
おじいちゃんたちの対話が―
You see, the well of Olympus is decided through
debate between Gaia and the Seven Elders.
オリュンポスの意思を生み出すの
（七賢老）ガイアは
それを設計した多くの科学者の―
Gaia is a composite system, a collection of wisdom
and acumen of the scientists who designed it.
知恵と意思の集合体だ
（七賢老）でも所詮 機械は機械
安定性に隙がない
But in the end it's still a machine.
Perfect in its stability.
揺らぎが皆無だ
It will never waver.
つまり 心や感情は持てない
ということだよ
In other words it has no emotion or
compassion for human sentiment.
我々７人のヒトの心が加わって
By adding our seven minds to
its collective understanding of humanity
ガイアの思考を
より柔軟にしているのだよ
we give Gaia's thinking a measure of flexibility.
でも 最近はガイアとよく
ケンカしてるわよね
However, lately all you seem to do is to disagree with it.
（七賢老）我々の仕事は 常に
ガイアと議論し続けることなんだよ
It is our duty as a counsel
to ensure an ongoing dialog between us and Gaia.
（七賢老）その 長い議論から
生み出された結論が―
The results of our continuing conversation with each other
オリュンポスを正しい未来へと導く
sets Olympus on the proper path towards the future.
デュナンは
昨日まで戦場にいたのだよね？
Till yesterday you were on the battlefield,
weren't you, Deunan?
何のために戦っていたんだね？
Please tell us
what were you fighting for?
それは…
Well, I...
ヒトは欲望の続く限り
戦いをやめない
Understand, as long as we allow desire to rule us the war will never end.
だから 我々は
このオリュンポスを作った
It's inevitable
building Olympus was the only solution.
（七賢老）ヒトとバイオロイドﾞの
共存こそが―
Coexistence between man and Bioroid
人類の最後の希望なんだよ
is the last remaining hope
for the survivals of our species.
（七賢老）ガイアは
そのバランスを監視している
And Gaia is ever watchful of that balance.
Bioroids are vastly different life forms from human beings.
（七賢老）バイオロイドは
ヒトとはずいぶん違う生き物でね
The reproductive functions remain inactive,
so they can produce no offspring.
（七賢老）生殖機能を持たないので
子孫繁栄ができない
セックスしないの
In other words, no sex.
（七賢老）それ故に
愛情を制御されているから―
And sense emotions such as love and hate are controlled.
欲望も少なく憎しみも希薄だ
Desire and entity are almost not existent.
（七賢老）しかし―
However,
because Bioroids cannot reproduce organically
（七賢老）定期的に寿命を延ばす
延齢(えんれい)処理を施さなければ
they must undergo a periodic life extension process.
急速に老化が進み
死に至る存在でもある
If not, their bodies will age rapidly
and die within a matter of hours.
（七賢老）我々はヒトとの
差別化を図るために―
This is how we differentiated the Bioroid species from our own.
バイオロイドの生殖機能を抑制し
そのライフサイクルを変化させた
By suppressing reproductive function
and altering their life cycles.
Hitomi,
ヒトミ 今回は 延齢処理が
遅れてるんじゃないか？
aren't you overdue for a life extension process yourself?
大丈夫よ
２ ３日中に必ず受けるから
Don't you worry.
I'll have the procedure done within the next few days.
いつか そんな面倒がなくなる日が
来るといいな
That's good.
I hope someday you won't have to go to all that trouble.
ゴトン！
（ランス班長）
クドー  おまえのチームも全滅した
Kudoh,
your entire unit's been wiped out.
Not bad at all... for beginners.
青いわね  あしからず
ナイフ１本でスタートして
10分で16人抜きか
She started with only a knife and within
10 minutes took out 16 of our men.
（ランス）
すごい新人を連れてきたな
That's one hell of a rookie you brought me.
いい気なもんだな
So...
You proud of yourself?
（ブリアレオス）
いつか自分の命を助けてくれる
かもしれない仲間に向かって―
Did it ever occurred to you that one of those
beginners might just save your life someday?
あんなことを言うもんじゃない
You should show them some respect.
久々に会えたのに 何か
他に言うことはないの？
Is that all you can say to me after we've been apart for so long?
Can’t you at least try to say something nice?
もっと ましなこと言えないの？
Like "how you been for the last few years?" or...
２年間どうしてたのか？ とか
再開できて嬉しいとか
"it's great to see you again"!
（ブリアレオス）
おまえは狙われている
Your life is in danger.
Don't you think I know that?
そんなこと分かってるわ
でも なぜ狙われるの？
But the question is why. Who's behind this?
あいつらは何者？
I don't know.
（ブリアレオス）
分からない
And what the hell is "Appleseed"?
（デュナン）
じゃあ アップルシードって何？
I don't know.
（ブリアレオス）分からない
そんな機械的な返事
聞きたくないわ！
Stop answering me like a damn machine!
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい…
（ブリアレオス）おまえを
守ることが 今の俺の任務だ
My mission is to make sure that nothing happens to you.
Your mission?..
任務って…
（ブリアレオス）明日(あした)も９時からだ
See you tomorrow at 9.
じゃあ 乾杯～
They didn't tell us we got our asses kicked by the legendary lady-warrior Deunan Knute.
（レイトン）まさか あんたが
あの伝説の女戦士―
デュナン･ナッツとはな
大戦で死んだって噂だったぜ
I heard you were killed in battle.
People are still talking about how badass you were during the last Global War.
非核大戦(ひかくたいせん)での活躍は
すでに語り草だからな
May I join you?
Go ahead.
どうぞ
Deunan,
デュナン…  カール･ナッツ…
your father...
What's he been you to all these years?
お父さんはどうしてるの？
He died from an illness before the War.
父は大戦前に病死したの
Oh...
そう…  お母さんは？
What about your mother?
I don't know. I can't remember.
母の記憶は 全くないの
父は何も話してくれなかったし
My father didn't talk about her that much.
So, tell me
デュナンって ブリアレオスと
恋人同士だったのよね？
you and Briareos used to be lovers, right?
He was still flesh and blood back then, so to speak.
彼が まだ生身の体だった頃の話よ
I guess looks count for a lot in love, ha?
恋では外見が重要ってことね
ウフ
そんなこと言ってないでしょ
That isn't what I meant at all.
It's a shame really.
もったいないわね
男としては正常なのに
He's still a man inside.
（ヒトミ）ねえ…
Deunan...
恋って どんな感じ？
What's it like to be in love?
What?
Bioroids were design with a limited capacity for emotion, remember?
バイオロイドは愛情が抑制
されてるって聞いたでしょう？
We don't know how it feels to really be in love.
だから恋する気持ちって
分からないの
Of course, I can understand it on the intellectual level,
（ヒトミ）情報としては
理解できるのよ  でも―
but love has little to do with intellect.
本質を感じることはできないの
It's emotion.
それなのに
興味ばっかり強くなっちゃって
That's what makes it so fascinating.
I know it's silly,
その点だけは
ヒトをうらやましいって思うのよね
but it's the one thing I envy about humans.
I always think it must be wonderful.
恋したときってどうなるの？
ヒトを愛するって…
To feel what love is like.
恋したときってどうなるの？
ヒトを愛するって…
（オリュンポス正規軍）
貴様！バイオロイドの分際で
ヒトにたてつくとは何事だ！
How dare you!
You got a lot of nerve
- talking to a human that way, Bioroid!
- I'm sorry, I was only...
（オリュンポス正規軍）
俺に口答えしたのか！
Olympus Regular Army.
オリュンポス正規軍よ
嫌ね  ヒトって
Anger...
That's one emotion I don't envy.
すぐに怒鳴ったりするんだから
（オリュンポス正規軍）
何も言えねえのか！
What? Say something!
Operation check complete.
（宮本(みやもと) 義経(よしつね)）動作確認 終了！
すべて問題なしと
This baby's ready for a test drive.
Once I adjust the cockpit settings, she's all yours.
あとは コックピット内の
シート調整だけだけど
Before she is, maybe you could clear something up for me.
（デュナン）その前に もう一度
確認しときたいんだけど
クッションや腱鞘(けんしょう)の
衝撃緩和剤(しょうげきかんわざい)が少ないのは…
Why are shock absorbers in the tendon sheath so minimum?
As I explained before so brilliantly,
それは さっきも説明したように
All forceful impact is absorbed directly through power train.
動力機構自体に
衝撃吸収性があるからで―
But there're plenty of cartilage units for enhanced mobility,
（義経）でも 軟骨ユニットも
やたらと多いし―
a magnetic fluid used in the triaxial joints as well as
oscillating bearings allow for precise sensory control.
３軸性関節やベアリングや知覚の
微振動制御は磁性流体部品だし
Don't get too crazy with it, though.
Or you could really get hurt.
余力に振り回されると
脱臼(だっきゅう)したりするよ
Relax, Yoshi, Deunan isn't someone you have to be worried about.
義経くん  デュナン･ナッツに
そんな心配はいらないわよ
I'm not. It's just that I've never seen a woman handle a Landmate before.
でも このランドメイトを
使いこなせる女性なんて―
（義経）普通いないし
No offence.
None taken. Why don't you adjust the seat, ok?
いいわ
乗るから シート調節して
Deunan, you're at good hands.
デュナン 義経くんって
オリュンポス一のメカニックなのよ
Yoshi is the best mechanic in Olympus.
As far as Landmates are concerned.
ランドメイトに限ってはね
But lately his passion's been for Hecatonchires units.
今は ヘカトンケイレスに
ご執心なのよね
Next time you gotta let me peak under the hood.
今度 ゆっくり中まで見せてよ
I think, I'll pass.
恥ずかしがり屋でね
遠慮しとくよ
I'm... kinda shy.
So, you feel secure?
ちゃんと締まってる？
Hm, it's fine.
うん 大丈夫
All right.
それじゃ
This is the ignition sequence for the engines.
（義経）
まず これが起動スイッチで
Start around slowly.
（義経）まずは 慣らし運転
ゆっくりと  そうそう
Try to get the feel for it.
That's good.
State of emergency. Scramble order.
What is it?
何？
That's the Code Red alert.
緊急出動警報だ！
Unidentified Landmates have infiltrated the Bioroid Care Center!
（アナウンス）
所属不明の
複数のランドメイトが
バイオロイド･ケアセンターに侵入
Multiple targets!
ES.W.A.T. units 104, 106,107!
ES.W.A.T.104  106  107…
Employ Landmates, encrypt with D-types and proceed to BCC stage immediately!
各階
ランドメイト  任意装備で出動！
現場へ急行せよ！
繰り返す…
Repeat.
Unidentified Landmates have infiltrated the Bioroid Care Center!
Multiple targets!
ES.W.A.T. units 104, 106,107!
Are you gonna stand here all day?
ぼやぼやするな！
行くぞ！
Forget it! I'm going in this!
いいから このまま行く
What?! Are you crazy?
（義経）このままって？
デュナン！
Deunan!
止めて！
Stop the tank!
来る…
They're close!
How to aim this thing?
（デュナン）照準は…
（ブリアレオス）デュナン！
Deunan!
（デュナン）あっ 待って  ダメだ
No! Get out of here!
ガソウしろ！
Dismount! Now!
（ブリアレオス）デュナン！
Deunan!
どおっ！
（デュナン）ブリアレオス…
Briareos.
（ブリアレオス）すまない…
Sorry.
なんという愚かなことを…
How could they do something so foolish?
（ニケ）第３期バイオロイドは
全滅です―
All third-gen Bioroids have been destroyed.
延齢処理用のＤＮＡオリジナルも
すべて焼き払われました
The fire wiped out all original DNA for life extension as well.
（ニケ）侵入経路はいずれも地下の
エレベーターシャフトからです
The perpetrators gained access from a subterranean elevator shaft.
（ニケ）７か所のセキュリティを
すべて１回でクリアしています
And one by one cleared all seven security points.
オリュンポス外部からの
侵入形跡はなく
Olympus perimeter shows no trace of entry.
ランドメイトの所属は不明です
Landmate origin is unknown.
ここまでやるとは…
I underestimated them.
我々は どうあってもヒトの原罪を
背負い込む運命なのだね
Alas...
I seems our destiny is to bear the sins of all humanity.
これで選択の余地はなくなった
There's only one option left to us now.
これより タルタロス ダイダロス
周辺を全面封鎖する
I want the perimeter around Tartarus and Daedalus sealed off at once.
（アテナ）頂上のＤタンクへは
何人たりとも近づけるな
No one gets close to D-Tank without my approval, understood?
Yes, Ma'am!
（ニケ）はい
（アテナ）
ただちに緊急議会を招集する
I'll arrange an emergency session at Congress.
デュナン 大丈夫かな
I hope Deunan's all right.
ヒトミ！
Hitomi!
まさか…
Oh, no!
Your life extension procedure...
延齢処理のリミットが ３日も
オーバーしているじゃないか！
You were due three days ago!
ヒトミ！ ヒトミ！
Hitomi! Hitomi!
（アテナ）ケアセンター襲撃を
おこなったランドメイトの所属
We have yet to identify the Landmates who attacked the Care Center
及び製造場所は特定できていません
or the location of their manufacturer.
That's the extend of the information ES.W.A.T. has about the incident at this time.
今回の事件に関する ES.W.A.T.
からの現状報告は以上です
I urge all Bioroids:
全バイオロイドの皆さん どうか
冷静に行動してください
Please, remain calm through this trial.
（アテナ）延齢処理に関しては
現在 対応策を検討中です
We are currently exploring every alternative method for life extension.
くれぐれも パニックを
起こすことのないように
Remember, panic will only worsen our cause.
（ウラノス）アテナ総監
Prime Minister Athena,
by having ES.W.A.T. seal off Tartarus and Daedalus,
それにしても ES.W.A.T.による―
タルタロス
ダイダロスの全面封鎖は―
have you not exceeded your authority as Prime Minister?
越権行為ではありませんか？
戒厳令に近い 非常時対応と
ご理解願いたい
The situation necessitate near-martial law conditions.
Our duty now is the protection of Gaia.
我々にはガイアを守る
義務があります
Ｄタンクではなく？
And not the D-Tank?
ガイアを守るためです
Gaia must be secured.
オリュンポス正規軍を差し置いて？
Without the aid of the Regular Army?
General, I stand by my decision.
最良の選択をしたまでです
What are you saying?!
どういう意味だ！
我々を侮辱する気か！
Are you trying to humiliate us?!
（七賢老）
今は そんなことで揉めている
ときではありません
General, please, we do not have the time for this sort of petty scrabbling.
皆さん 今回のテロは―
Now then...
Congressmen of Olympus.
This terrorist act was an attempted Bioroid genocide.
バイオロイドﾞの
存在意義を根底から覆し―
オリュンポスを揺るがす大惨事です
It has rocked the foundation of our society.
As it presently stands,
このままでは バイオロイドの
未来は完全に閉ざされてしまいます
the future of all Bioroid life
has been destroyed by this catastrophe.
However,
しかし 彼らを救い オリュンポスを
この危機から守る方法が―
hope still exists.
There's yet a way to ensure the survival of their race.
一つだけ残されています
A permanent form of life extension.
（七賢老）その方法の
是非に関しては長く―
Its implementation will save Olympus from this calamity.
非常に長く 我々とガイアの間で
議論を重ねてきました
For a long time
the Elders have been discussing the pros and cons of this method with Gaia.
（七賢老）そして ガイアはついに
決断を下しました
Finally, after much deliberation
Gaia has made its decision.
So be it.
ガイアはバイオロイドを活性化し
As a solution to this crisis
生殖機能を復活させることを
支持しました
we will restore all Bioroid reproductive functions.
What!?
I was my understanding that the technological data
バイオロイドの生殖機能復活の
テクノロジーは―
needed to reactivate such functions in Bioroids
開発者であるギリアム博士が―
have been destroyed by its inventor Dr. Gilliam.
その基礎データを抹消したため
再開発不可能だと聞いていますが？
Which would make recovering the original data impossible.
Your understanding is correct.
その通りです ウラノス将軍
その基礎データが―
The original data would indeed be impossible to recover.
本当に消滅していたのなら
再開発は不可能でしょう
Had it actually been destroyed?
However,
（七賢老）ところが
失われたはずの基礎データ―
it is recently come to our attention that Dr. Gilliam's data,
我々がアップルシードと名付けた
そのデータは―
which we have named "Appleseed",
現在も存在するのです
is still in existence.
（七賢老）我々は もうすぐ
We are confident
that our attempt in retrieving the lost Appleseed will be successful.
失われたアップルシードに
辿(たど)り着くでしょう
Once found
そして バイオロイドの
生殖機能を復活し―
Bioroid reproductive capabilities will be restored.
彼らを新人類へと進化させ
They will evolve into a new race of Man
新たな楽園を創造するのです！
and create a shining paradise for us all!
ハア… ハア…
Hitomi!
ヒトミ！
Do not worry.
（七賢老）
大丈夫 眠っているだけだ
She is merely asleep.
Will you be able to save her?
本当に助かるのですか？
If we can find Appleseed, Hitomi will recover.
失われたアップルシードさえ
見つかれば
What will happen if you don't?
見つからなければ？
She will age at an alarming rate.
急激な老化を始め
24時間以内に死ぬことになる
Her life functions will cease in 24 hours.
（アテナ）
ヒトミだけじゃない
It's not just Hitomi.
An accelerating death is the fate awaiting all Bioroids.
バイオロイドすべてが いずれ
同じ運命を辿ることになる
Including myself.
I'm Athena Areios, Prime Minister of Olympus.
行政総監 アテナ･アレイアスだ
（アテナ）デュナン･ナッツだね？
You must be Deunan Knute.
Deunan.
（七賢老）デュナン
Have you heard of the scientist Dr. Gilliam?
ギリアム博士を知っているかい？
No.
いいえ…
We've been conducting our own research for over twenty years now
我々は20年間 研究を重ねたが―
and have yet to surpass the late Doctor's achievement in Bioroid technology.
今は亡きギリアム博士を
未だに超えることができない
しかし 博士の開発した
アップルシードさえ手に入れば―
True.
But if we acquire the Appleseed data Dr. Gilliam developed
organic reproduction will be restored to their species.
バイオロイドは生殖機能を
取り戻すことができる
（七賢老）そして Ｄタンクの
恐怖からも開放され―
They'll be freed from the lumen fear of the D-Tank
永遠の種族
新人類となりうるのだよ
and become new, eternal race of mankind.
Indeed, Gaia has made its decision.
（七賢老）ガイアは
ついに決意した
Now, Athena,
さあ アテナ
次はあなたの番だ
it is time for you to make yours.
Deunan.
デュナン
我々に力を貸して欲しい
I'm going to need your help to find it.
So, this old disc is the only clue we've got?
（デュナン）この古い
ディスクだけが手掛かりだなんて…
We're heading for the lab where the first generation of Bioroids was created, right?
これから向かう研究施設で―
第１期のバイオロイドは
生まれたの？
（ブリアレオス）そう聞いている
That's what they told me.
If Athena had the disc, why do you think she kept it secret all this time?
アテナ総監は なぜ 今まで
このディスクを隠し続けたの？
And if Bioroid reproduction is so important
（デュナン）
そもそもギリアム博士は―
なぜ バイオロイドの生殖機能の
復活を封印してしまったの？
why would Dr. Gilliam wanna seal away the original data?
Deunan, listen...
（ブリアレオス）
デュナン―
これは秘密裏に行わなければ
ならない危険なミッションだ
this is a highly classified mission that's gonna put us all at risk.
If completing it will save Hitomi's life, isn't that enough?
（ブリアレオス）
我々は任務の遂行に集中して―
結果 ヒトミが助かれば
それでいいじゃないか
Just stay focused on her and try not to think too much.
Everything else is only a distraction.
（ブリアレオス）あまり
余計なことを考えないほうがいい
Mind if I ask one more question?
一つだけ聞いていい？
Yeah.
That last shot you fired at the terrorist...
テロのときの最後の銃弾…
あれは…
Did you...
No, just forget it. Never mind.
いや… なんでもない 忘れて
（クドー）ん？
デュナン！ レイトン！ こっちだ！
Deunan! Leyton, over here.
This must what we're looking for.
（デュナン）
これに間違いなさそうね
クドー 下がって！
Kudoh, get back!
Dr. Gilliam, there's no time!
（アテナ）ギリアム博士！
時間がありません
早く逃げてください！
- You've got to get out of here!
- Athena...
（ギリアム博士）アテナ
もう少しです
Just give me a second. I have to destroy it.
（ギリアム）
これだけは処分しなければ
I'll try to hold them on the first floor. But you have to hurry!
１階で食い止めますから
とにかく早く！
Mommy.
What's wrong, honey? Did we wake you up?
どうしたの？
起きちゃったの？
Oh, my God...
そんな…
What is it, Deunan?
どうした？ デュナン
It's her...
母さん…
Deunan, listen very carefully.
（ギリアム）
デュナン よーく聞いて
You see this pendant?
このペンダントには ママの大切な
研究データが記録してあるの
Mommy's very important research data is inside of it.
But there're some very bad people out there.
でも 悪いヒトたちがママの研究を
良くないことに使おうとしているの
And if they find it they'll use it to do some very bad things.
That's why I'm hiding it in this.
だから ママは研究データを
隠しちゃうことにしたの
So they'll never find it.
The bad people want it?
悪いヒトたち？
Yes.
そう デュナンたちの未来を
奪おうとする悪いヒトたち
They want to take away your future.
You understand?
That's why I'm giving it to you,
（ギリアム博士）だからデュナンが
このペンダントを守ってね
so you can keep it safe.
うん デュナンが守る
Okay, don't worry, mommy.
いい子ね
Good girl.
デュナン でも もし アテナが
欲しいって言ったら
Deunan,
one more thing.
If Athena ever asks you for it,
このペンダントはアテナに渡してね
I want you to give the pendant to her, all right?
アテナだけは特別
Athena is very special.
分かった
アテナだけは 特別
I understand. Athena is very special.
デュナン
アップルシードを守ってね
Deunan,
you must protect the Appleseed.
デュナン 分かったんだな
目的のものがどこにあるのか―
Deunan, you remember now, don't you?
Where is it?
Where did she hide the data?
（ブリアレオス）
思い出したんだな
カールの銃―
Carl's gun...
そのペンダントに
アップルシードが入ってるんだな
that pendant...
And Appleseed's inside of it, isn't it?
Dr. Gilliam, I presume.
ギリアム博士ですね
どうかそのまま動かないでください
Stay where you are. We don't want to hurt you.
あ… 動かないで…
Don't do it!..
お願いだから 動かないで…
Please, for God's sake, don't...
（デュナン幼少）ママ
どうしたの？  ママ？
Mommy. What's wrong, mommy?
（ギリアム）
デュナン…  来ないで！
Deunan, stay out!
撃たないでー！
No! Don't shoot!
（デュナン）母さん…
まずい オリュンポス軍だ
いつの間に…
What the hell... It's the Army!
Come in hot!
（ブリアレオス）
どうやってここが…
How did they know about this?
結構な数だぜ
すでに階下は抑えられてる
They've got the deck surrounded. We're gonna find another way out.
屋上への通路は１本だ
屋上で迎え撃つぞ！
There's only one way straightaway to the roof.
We can cut out them from there.
（レイトン）おーっと
みんな動かないでくれ
Sorry, guys, but I can't let you do that.
５階のＤ研究室だ
We're in Lab D, Level 5.
レイトン  おまえ！
裏切ったのか！
You're son of a bitch!
You betrayed us!
昔から バイオロイドは嫌いでね
What can I say. I've always hated Bioroids.
（ハデス）それに 裏切ったのは
そいつが先だぜ！
Besides,
the real traitor is right there.
ハデス！
Hades.
デュナン  久しぶりだな
Deunan, how nice to see you.
カールは俺の手で
あの世に送ってやりたかった
I only wish I'd had the honor of killing your father.
You've got the stink of Bioroid all over you, you know that?
やっぱり おまえも
バイオロイドのにおいがするな
それにしても
こんな機械の塊になっても―
What a nice surprise to see you and Briareos together again.
まだ ご一緒とは泣かせるね
Of course, he's not the man he used to be, right?
じいさんたちの茶番には
正直 恐れ入ったよ
I got fed up with those old fossils and their terrorist farce.
だが 部下を信用しすぎるのは
昔からの悪い癖だな ブリアレオス
Well...
Lucky for us you made the classic mistake of trusting your subordinates.
What a fool.
Briareos, what's he talking about?
ブリアレオス  どういうこと？
（ハデス）俺が教えてやるよ
Let me spell it out for you, Deunan.
デュナン―
The attack on the Bioroid Care Center was aided by none other then Briareos.
ケアセンター襲撃を
持ち掛けてきたのは―
このブリアレオスさ
テロのとき
俺が乗ったランドメイトを―
Don't look so surprised.
You saw how easily he let my Landmate escape, didn't you?
こいつが逃してくれたのを
覚えているだろう？
この男のせいで
バイオロイドは死滅するのだよ
And thanks to him, every last Bioroid is going to die.
本当なの？
Is this true?
Well, go on, answer her!
答えてやりなよ
けっ… ●の犬め！
Legislature patsy.
（ハデス）さあ そのペンダントを
渡してもらおうか
Now.
I'll take that pendant, if you please.
（ブリアレオス）デュナン！
上に逃げるんだ！  早く！
Deunan!
Get to the roof!
Let's go!
クドー！
- Kudoh!
- Come on!
行くぞ！
来ないで！
Stay back!
Don't come any closer!
それ以上近寄らないで！
デュナン
そのペンダントは俺が引き受ける
Deunan, please, you have to give me that pendant.
（ブリアレオス）それさえ手放せば
おまえは安全だ！
As long as you have it you'll never be safe!
My mother gave her life to protect this and so will I!
これは母が命をかけて
守ったものなのよ！
全部 知ってたのね  初めから…
You knew it all along, didn't you?
You knew everything!
全部知っていたのね
デュナン…
Deunan.
Deunan!
デュナン！  ようやく分かったろ
その化け物の正体が！
Now you see what he is. What kind of monster he has become.
（ウラノス）
デュナン･ナッツ！
Deunan Knute.
I am Edward Uranus III, Commander of the Regular Army.
オリュンポス軍総司令
エドワード･ウラノス３世だ！
Your father, Carl Knute, and I were comrades.
カール･ナッツとは
古くからの戦友で―
And I knew Dr. Gilliam very well.
ギリアム博士もよく知っている
We met on many occasions when you were young.
（ウラノス）
何度か小さい頃の君にもあっている
Deunan,
（ウラノス）我々は
君に危害を与えるつもりはない
you must understand we have no intention of harming you.
（ウラノス）そのデータを
消去できればそれで良い
We only wish to see that data destroyed.
我々は これより立法院を占拠
Our goal is to regain control of the Legislature,
Ｄタンクを破壊し
バイオロイドを一掃する
destroy the D-Tank thus ridding the world of Bioroids.
もう一度 ヒトの手に
ヒト社会を取り戻すのだ
When that's achieved
society will once again be under human control.
だが そのデータは
クーデターの妨げになる
The only thing standing in the way of our success is that data.
どうか 大人しく
それを渡してくれないか
Now, please, would you hand it over without further incidents?
Request denied!
お断りします
Deunan!
デュナン！
Deunan.
デュナン
Olympus was supposed to be a utopia for mankind
オリュンポスは もはや―
カールやギリアム博士が夢見た
but the world your parents envisioned for us has failed.
ユートピアでは
なくなってしまったのだ
All those years the only thing my father ever taught me how to do is how to fight.
私は 父カールから
戦うことだけを教え込まれました
It's funny. I never understood why he pushed me so hard to become a soldier.
でも 父が なぜ私を
戦闘マシーンとして鍛え上げたのか
But he forged me into warrior for a reason.
その訳が 今ようやく分かった
気がします
General,
将軍
as my mother instructed, I will give this data only to Athena.
母の遺言どおりこのデータは
アテナ以外には渡せません
And by doing so you will seal our fate.
（ウラノス）バイオロイドを
信用してはいけない！
（ウラノス）彼らは
ヒトを支配下に置こうとしている
You mustn't trust Bioroids. They want to control us!
（デュナン）そうかもしれない
信用できないかもしれない
Maybe you're right.
Maybe they can't be trusted.
But after what I've seen I know this much:
でも 一つだけ
はっきりしていることがあります
Bioroids don't try to kill each other!
バイオロイドはバイオロイドを
殺さないわ！
将軍 時間の無駄です
General, you're wasting your time.
You're right.
デュナン… 残念だ
What a pity.
（ブリアレオス）アテナは
ヒト社会を守ろうとしている！
Athena is trying to protect our society.
Carl and Dr. Gilliam gave their lives
（ブリアレオス）
カールもギリアム博士も―
trying to hide Appleseed for the sake of humanity.
ヒト社会を守るために 命がけで
アップルシードを隠したんだ！
They both feared what would happen when the Bioroids were activated.
２人はバイオロイドの活性化を
恐れていた…
Because the Bioroids represent a threat to our race.
それは バイオロイドは
危険な存在だからだ
No.
違う！
Athena honored Dr. Gilliam's request to keep their reproductive systems inactive.
博士の意思をついで アテナは
活性化を拒み続けてきたんだ
General...
将軍
The Bioroids' purpose is to safeguard our species.
バイオロイドは
ヒト社会を守ろうとしている
俺がハデスと組んで
テロを誘発したのは
Deunan,
I cooperated with Hades and the terrorist attack to force Athena's hand.
アテナが バイオロイドの活性化に
応じるよう仕向けるためだったんだ
I knew she would have no choice but to fully activate the Bioroids.
（ブリアレオス）
ショックで失われた
デュナンの記憶を辿る鍵を―
She'd been hiding the key that would unlock your memory of Appleseed's location.
アテナは最後まで隠そうとしていた
Your memory was long repressed by the shock of your mother's death.
（ブリアレオス）俺の任務は―
It was my duty to deliver Appleseed to the Elders.
アップルシードを
じいさんたちに届けるまでだ
And in return, they would guarantee your safety.
それでデュナンの安全は
保障されることになっていた
（ウラノス）
では なおさら そのペンダントを
破棄しなければいけない
Don't you see?
That's all the more reason you have that pendant destroyed.
But, General, there's more going on here.
（ブリアレオス）将軍！
何かがおかしい！
The Elders don't simply want to get their hand on the Appleseed data.
じいさんたちが望んでいるのは
アップルシードだけではない！
じいさんたちは
クーデターを必要とし
They needed you and the Regular Army to attempt a coup.
Ｄタンクの破壊を望んでいる
They want you to blow up the D-Tank.
There must be some reason why Athena is so desperate to prevent that from happening.
アテナがＤタンクを
死守しているのには―
何か理由があるはずだ
General, please, D-Tank must not be destroyed!
将軍…
Ｄタンクを破壊してはいけない！
No, Briareos!
ブリアレオス！
I've heard enough.
我々が
And I'll be damned if I let some machine tell us what to do!
機械の言うことなどに
惑わされるわけがないだろう！
This is vengeance, Deunan!
復讐だ！ デュナン！
It was your father who kicked me out of the LA S.W.A.T.
L.A.S.W.A.T.を除隊させられた後
どれだけ惨めな日々が続いたか―
Do you know how many years of humiliation I suffered because of him?!
おまえには想像できないだろう
デュナン！
Finally!
これは 俺を除隊に追い込んだ
カールへの復讐だ！
I get to pay him back for all the misery he caused.
His DNA is inside of everyone of those things!
やつの遺伝子の存在すら
吐き気がするぜ
When the Bioroids are dead,
バイオロイドは皆殺しにしてやる！
Carl's legacy will be erased!
Hades!
ハデス…
Deunan!
デュナン！
恨むんなら 親父を恨むんだな！
If you wanna blame someone, blame your father!
（ブリアレオス）すまない
Forgive me.
Don't talk.
しゃべらないで…
最新のサイボーグでも
撃たれると痛いな
Just think they could wire me.
Do not feel the pain.
Would you stop trying to talk?
お願いだからしゃべらないで
God, I missed you...
会いたかった…
戦場で死にかけたとき…
As I lay dying on the battlefield,
どうしてもおまえに
もう一度会いたかった
all I wanted was to see you again...
The Elders brought me back to life...
そして じいさんたちに救われた
You were the only thing that mattered to me.
（ブリアレオス）
おまえが助かるのであれば―
他のことは もう
どうでも良くなっていた
I would've done everything to make sure you were safe...
（デュナン）もう分かったから
I know that now.
（ブリアレオス）俺は身も心も
化け物になってしまった…
I've become a monster on the inside as well.
あなたは何も変わらないわ
昔のまま
Don't say that. You haven't changed.
You're still the same.
でも… もう おまえを守ることは
できなくなった…
I wanted to protect you...
But I can't anymore...
あなたを死なせない
I won't let you die.
デュナン  ヒトには… ゴホッ…
ゴホッ…
Deunan, the Elders...
ブリアレオス！
Briareos!
ヒトには１人の
犠牲者も出さないと
The Elders promised no loss of human life.
But something else is going on.
じいさんたちは約束したんだ
That's why you have to go.
（ブリアレオス）
でも 何かが進行している
だから… 行くんだ
Hurry!
Before it's to late...
でも あなたを置いてはいけない…
No, Briareos, I won't leave you.
You have to...
この星の未来がかかってるのだ
The future depends on it...
あなたのいない未来なんて…
There's no future without you.
Deunan...
デュナン…
don't let your mother's death...
お母さんの死を
無駄にしてはいけ… あ…
be for nothing.
もう しゃべらないで！
Please, stop trying to talk.
デュナン…
Deunan...
ブリアレオス？
Briareos?
ブリアレオス～！
Briareos!
We picked up an SOS from Briareos on the secure line after he was shot.
撃たれた直後に
ブリアレオスから―
シークレットラインで
ＳＯＳが入った
さすがにヘカトンケイレスは
作りが違うな
His Hecatonchires units are built like nothing else.
組織閉鎖が間に合ってる
His system shot down in time.
（義経）まだ 助かるかもしれない
I may still be able to revive him.
助けて…
Bring him back.
お願い…
Save him.
（義経）
燃料は運んできたから問題ない
Don't worry about the fuel. She's got the full tank.
ランドメイトのダミュソスは
すでに実用段階だし―
The new Landmate Damysos System makes her pretty smooth flying once you get hanging.
飛行は思ったより安定している
Just be aware that she is a little top-heavy.
（義経）機体の重心が
やや上方にずれているが―
If you keep you turns out of 60 degrees it shouldn't be a problem.
60度までの旋回に影響はない
デュナン
Deunan...
僕たちバイオロイドにだって
わずかながら愛情が存在するんだ
Bioroid emotions might be suppressed,
but that doesn't mean that we can't feel love.
Save Hitomi.
ヒトミを頼む
デュナン･ナッツ
任務完了いたしました
Deunan Knute reporting. Mission accomplished.
ご苦労！
Good work.
デュナン…
Deunan.
Well done, Deunan, well done!
（七賢老）
デュナン！ 良くやった！
Thanks to you
我々は ついに バイオロイドの
生殖機能復活に成功したよ
Bioroid reproductive functions have at last been activated.
Hitomi's regenerative cycle is becoming like that of a human being.
（七賢老）
ヒトミの生命維持サイクルも
ヒトのそれに同期し始めた
（七賢老）これでヒトミは助かる
The life will be spared.
良かった…
Thank goodness.
It's all right. There's no need to worry.
もう 心配はいらないよ
デュナン？
Deunan...
It was you who killed her, wasn't it?
母を殺したのはあなたたちですか？
You murdered my mother, didn't you?
あなたたちが殺したの？
Deunan, please forgive us.
デュナン 許してくれ
あれは本当に事故だったんだ
Your dear mother's death was an accident.
Her research was invaluable.
博士を失わなければ 我々には
他の選択があったかもしれない
Had she been alive today we might have had other options.
If that's the case then why she had to hide the Appleseed data?
（デュナン）
母は なぜアップルシードを
隠さなければならなかったの？
我々は
博士にわずかな希望をもらった
Understand. Her work gave us a chance of survival.
Bioroids. A new form of life that could help us save our own.
ヒトが種族として生き残るための
最後のチャンス
ヒトとバイオロイドの共存こそが
唯一の希望だった
Man was doomed,
but coexistence with this new species
gave us all a glimmer of hope.
しかし ヒトはどうあっても
争うことをやめない
Even so,
human race could not suppress its violent nature.
異なる種族を恐れ 忌み嫌う
Mankind despises those that are different.
Once again he's come to hatred and anger.
憎しみと怒りに満ちあふれている
ヒトには もう この星を
維持していく力はない
And fear. He no longer has the ability to maintain this planet.
Human nature has caused the abuse of Dr. Gilliam's vision.
ヒトは博士の理想をも踏みにじった
Gaia has made an accurate prediction
（七賢老）ガイアの正確な予測では
人類は３世代のうちに―
that the human race is doomed to annihilate itself
地球と共に滅んでしまう
運命なのだよ
and destroy the world in three generations.
Deunan...
デュナン
Our time has passed.
我々 ヒトは
もう身を引くときがきたのだよ
The human race must step aside.
Step aside?
身を引く？
我々 ヒトは バイオロイドに
地球の未来を委ねなければならない
If the world is to survive
we have no choice but to relinquish its future to the Bioroids.
（七賢老）ギリアム博士が
自ら開発したウイルスが―
Dr. Gilliam spent many months creating a virus.
The time has finally come for it to serve its purpose.
ようやくその使命を
果たすときがきた
The virus my mother created?
母が開発したウイルス？
Yes.
（七賢老）
そう タルタロスの頂上にある
It has been sealed off in D-Tank on the top of Tartarus for many years,
Ｄタンクに
長く封印されてきたウイルス
waiting to be released.
（七賢老）そのウイルスは―
When the Tank is destroyed
the virus
ヒトの生殖機能を
完全に奪い去る
will make the entire human race permanently infertile.
We swore the no human life would be taken.
ヒトには１人の犠牲者も出ない
And so it won't.
我々は 緩やかに人の歴史を
閉じることになる
Instead, we will slowly close the book on human history.
The last chapter will be the euthanasia of mankind.
これは ヒトの安楽死なんだよ
My mother must have known.
母は反対したのね
バイオロイドの活性化を拒んだのね
And when she refused to fully activate the Bioroid you murdered her!
だから殺された！
We developed the plans for Olympus with two options in mind.
オリュンポス計画の選択肢は
二つだった
The world of Human and Bioroid coexistence
（七賢老）バイオロイドとの共存か
新人類への移譲か
or one bequeathed to a new race.
（七賢老）
その正確で 公平な判断を
委ねるためにガイアは作られたのだ
Gaia was created to ensure that all decisions were precise and balanced.
Dr. Gilliam contributed greatly to Gaia's creation
（七賢老）ガイアの創造には
ギリアム博士も大きく貢献した
instilling it with the understanding of both species.
It was as if Gaia had inherited your mother's tenacity.
（七賢老）博士の意思は
ガイアにも確かに受け継がれ―
For the virus could not be released from D-Tank by the will of Man.
ガイアの総意が得られなければ―
ウイルスの発動は不可能となった
It could only be released with Gaia's consent.
But even utopia could not quell man's need for violence.
（七賢老）ところが―
ヒトは再び世界大戦を始め―
Once again he became embroiled in a global war.
この星すべてを廃墟にしてしまった
And reduced the world to ashes.
（七賢老）世界を制圧したはずの
オリュンポスもこのざまだ
And now...
Olympus too has been marched by the sins of humanity.
The hatred of Bioroids
（七賢老）ウラノス将軍たちの
バイオロイドに対する憎悪は―
that's displayed by General Uranus and the Regular Army
ガイアの怒りを増幅させた
has fueled Gaia's anger.
It had no choice
そして ついに
ガイアは審判を下した
but to render this decision.
We will use Appleseed.
アップルシードにより
バイオロイドは―
The Bioroids will then create a new species.
新しい種の起源となり
And mankind will be eradicated from the planet.
ヒトは地上から
消え去るときがきた
So, you used us.
利用したのね
I was simply the bait to get Briareos to do what you wanted.
私を餌に
ブリアレオスを利用したのね！
It was all to force Gaia into making this decision!
みんな ガイアの決意を
促すためだったのね
ガイアを欺くためだったのね
You manipulated Gaia.
Deunan, it is humanity's destiny!
ヒトの定めだ デュナン
The moment I press this button
（七賢老）
このスイッチを押せば―
the D-Tank on Tartarus will be destroyed
タルタロスのＤタンクは爆発し
ウイルスが世界を飲み込む
and the virus will envelop the Earth.
Hold it right there!
そこまでだ  ご老体
Grid 984G, cut the power.
９-Ａ ４-Ｇだ
すぐに切断せよ
We've just rendered that button inactive.
これで そのスイッチは
無力化された
何の真似かな？ アテナ
Athena, what are you doing?
You seemed to have forgotten our primary function:
ヒトの滅亡を阻止するために―
to ensure the survival of the human race.
バイオロイドが作られたことを
お忘れですか？
That may be.
バイオロイドは―
But Bioroids were also programmed not to disobey us.
ヒトに逆らうようには
プログラムされてはいないはずだが
We are no longer the Bioroids you created,
我々は もうバイオロイドではなく
新人類と呼んでいただこう
but members of a new race.
Athena, the will of Gaia is irrefutable!
（七賢老）アテナ
これはガイアの意思なのだよ―
Its anger goes beyond General Uranus's actions
ウラノスの反乱に対する怒りであり
ヒトの原罪に対する報いだ
to encompass the sins of all humanity!
General Uranus has just surrendered. The coup d'etat is over.
ウラノス将軍は
たった今 クーデターを断念し
He seeks a full reconciliation.
和睦を申し入れてきました
The General surrendered?
将軍が？
I'm sure that Gaia is well aware of the impact of these recent events.
（アテナ）もちろん そのことを
ガイアが知らない訳がありませんが
Deunan,
デュナン ここには もう
ガイアの意思は存在していない
the will of Gaia is not present in this room.
But how can that be?
ガイアがいない？
Man's hatred for us has lessened.
（アテナ）ヒトの憎悪が薄れた今
ガイアは審判を覆したはず
Gaia would have sensed this and reverse its decision.
彼らは すでにガイアを停止させ
自らの意思だけで行動している
So the Elders shut Gaia down and have been acting on their own.
How very astute of you, Athena.
頼もしいよ アテナ
The new race of Man is wonderful indeed.
新人類は 実に素晴らしい
But Gaia regulates your life-support systems.
ガイアが停止したということは―
あなたたちの生命維持装置にも
多大な影響が出ているはず
Haven't you put your own lives at risk by shutting it down?
そう 我々と共に
ヒトは終焉(しゅうえん)を迎えるのだよ
That is correct.
We accept the fate of our race and intend to perish along with the rest.
Look!
多脚砲台が…
The Mobil Fortress!
た… 多脚砲台が一斉に立ち上がり
The Mobil Fortress platforms have been activated.
オリュンポス内部に
侵入を開始しました
They're heading to the center of Olympus!
多脚砲台は
タルタロスの頂上を目指している！
They have been programmed to destroy the D-Tank on Tartarus.
（七賢老）もう 誰にも
止めることはできない
There's nothing that can stop them now.
全ES.W.A.T.に告ぐ！
Attention ES.W.A.T. units!
（ニケ）すべてのランドメイトに
ダミュソスを装備！
Equip all Landmates with Damysos systems and deploy immediately!
全方位から多脚を攻撃
何としても食い止めろ！
Destroy the Mobil Fortress!
Use any means to bring them down!
Ｄタンクの防衛システムは
完全なはずでしょ？
I thought security around D-Tank was impenetrable.
多脚砲台の主砲に至近距離で
撃たれるというのは想定していない
A close range shot from one of the main gun turrets could breach the system.
（七賢老）絶対の剣と完全な盾
力に頼る者の悲劇だよ
The ultimate sword versus the perfect shield.
It's the fate of those who cling to power.
この速度だと
タルタロスまであと15分！
At their current speed, they'll reach Tartarus in 15 minutes.
（アテナ）住民の避難は？
Evacuate the city!
（ニケ）
ポリスが全力で当たっています
The police have already begun.
That's our top priority!
（アテナ）最優先させろ
（アテナ）多脚が無人のエリアに
入ったら 一斉攻撃をかける
Once the platforms reach unpopulated area we'll attack them on mass.
（ヒトミ）
第７多脚砲台が すべての
砲台の司令塔になっているわ
Concentrate on platform 7.
It's the control node for the entire Fortress.
（デュナン）ヒトミ！
Hitomi!
ヒトミ…
Hitomi...
ごめんね… おじいちゃんたち…
Forgive me.
But I have no choice.
（ヒトミ）先頭部にある
コントロールボックスで
If someone can disable the control box on the frontal cortex of No.7,
７号機を停止させれば
すべての多脚砲台が停止するはず
it will shut down the rest of the platforms.
破壊しては駄目！
The sequence is specific.
Destroying the box won't work.
７号機を手動で停止させるのよ
It has to be done manually.
制御停止のパスワードは…
The password to shut down the system is "hitomi".
“HITOMI(ヒトミ)”
ブリアレオス！
Briareos!
デュナン！ 約束したろ！
You asked and I delivered.
デュナン！ さあ 行くぞ！
飛び降りるんだ！
Well?
Don't you stand there. Come on! Jump!
It is futile.
（七賢老）もう 間に合わない！
ヒトは必ず地球を滅ぼすことになる
It's the fate of Man to destroy this world!
デュナン！  ヒトには もう
戻るべき楽園はないんだ
Deunan, we've been cast from Eden and cannot return.
So you're gonna give up and pass on our mistakes to the next race?
ヒトの罪を新人類へなすり付ければ
それで済むの？
We may have lost our chance at Eden,
例え そこが楽園でなくても
私たちは生き抜いてみせる
but we have to try to survive!
自分達の未来は
自分達で掴んでみせる！
We have to believe the future is what we make of it!
（ブリアレオス）デュナン！
Deunan!
It's not good. They're covered on all sides.
駄目だ どこにも死角はない
Gun platforms approaching Tartarus! Range: 2,000 meters!
多脚砲台 タルタロスまで
あと2000メートル！
Our weapons are ineffective! We can't stop them!
我々の●は 全く効果がない
（ニケ）ランス班長
７号機に取りつく 援護してくれ
Squad Leader, I'm heading for No.7. Cover me!
７号機は？
So, which one is it?
中央にいるやつだ
There. In the middle.
Fire all weapons at the legs of the platforms 6 and 8!
左右の６号機と８号機の足を狙え
（ランス）先行している５号機は？
What about No.5 in front?
（ニケ）かまわん  全勢力で
６号機と８号機を集中攻撃せよ
Forget it. Concentrate your fire on the two platforms pointing No.7!
No.6 is down!
６号機停止！
Good.
よし ８号機のほうは
どうなってる？
What's the progress on No.8?
There it is!
（ブリアレオス）あいつだ！
I'll head up in the crossfire.
（ブリアレオス）
俺が攻撃を引き付ける！
デュナンは足元から近づけ！
You should have a clear approach from beneath.
Got it!
（デュナン）分かった！
ブリアレオス！
Briareos!
Deunan!
デュナン！
多脚がタルタロスに到達！
登り始めました
The platforms have reached Tartarus!
They're beginning their ascend!
Deunan! Hurry!
デュナン！ 時間がない！
Three of the platforms are closing in on the D-Tank!
（ニケ）多脚砲台３機が
タンクに迫っている
We can't hold them up any longer!
もう 食い止めることができない！
What's wrong?
どうして…
It's not working!
（デュナン）なぜなの！？
Briareos!
ブリアレオス！
Deunan, let me go!
デュナン 手を離すんだ！
Forget it! I won't lose you again!
できる訳ないでしょ！
そんなこと！
The password! Hurry!
早くパスワードを！
Mother... Help me!
母さん…
They all stopped.
止まった…
すべての多脚が停止
Ｄタンクは無事です
All platforms have shut down.
D-Tank is secured!
Briareos!
ブリアレオス！
Deunan!
デュナン！
（デュナン）ヒトミ！
Take it easy.
アイタタタタ…
Sorry.
Are the Elders all right?
おじいちゃんたちは？
I see...
そう…
But the final letter of the password...
じゃあ あの最後の一文字は？
It's been left to us.
（ブリアレオス）任されたんだ
It's all been left to us now.
俺たちは任されたんだ
It's not as if anything has changed.
（デュナン）
何かが変わったわけではなかった
And giving enough time...
きっと 何も変わらないことが
I suppose the sins of humanity will only get worse.
ヒトの罪を
更に深くしていくのだろう
But there's always a chance that the next
generation might learn from our mistakes.
それでも 私は戦い続ける
So, I'll keep fighting...
私たちの子供たち
for our children's sake,
本当の意味での新人類のために
the true new race of Man.
A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release